Romulo Goncalves

Phone: (334)764-2467

Email: romulojusto@gmail.com Located in: Orlando, FL, 32820

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/romulo-g-45602539/

Portfolio: https://krooksoma.github.io/Portfolio/

Github: https://github.com/krooksoma

Summary

Full-Stack Software Developer with experience helping companies optimize project planning and execution that focuses on optimization and adaptability to customer needs. My passion for programming, aligned with my previous experience managing demanding projects has taught me how to approach a project at each unique step of its implementation. I have a Full Stack Web Developer Certificate from the University of Central Florida, as well as a Doctorate degree in Veterinary Medicine from Universidade Federal de Goiás, Brazil. I currently work with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MERN stack. I am expanding my knowledge in Java with a Certification, and am learning to work with cloud services such as Amazon and Oracle. As IT is an ever-increasing field with endless opportunities, I am excited to grow exponentially within this path..

Technical Skills

Tools & Technology

Languages: CSS, HTML, Javascript, Node.js, Apollo.js, and Java.

Databases: MySOL, MongoDB

Tools: Git and Heroku

Completed Projects

Clean Water Project

Github: https://github.com/shannonjburris/Clean water project

Deployed Project: https://algae-busters-clean-water-proj.herokuapp.com/

My team created a full-stack project using JavaScript, MySQL, HTML, and CSS. Our project's mission was to create awareness about the algae issue that has become common in FL. The platform is used by the user to document any occurrence in their area. They are able to create new posts with pictures and the county location. They are also able to comment on other users' posts. I was responsible for all back-end of this project but images and maps sections.

Do You Even Funko?

Github: https://github.com/krooksoma/FinalProject

Deployed Project: https://guarded-sierra-75793.herokuapp.com/

A Full-Stack MERN application I developed solely. The application focuses on allowing the user to create a database with their Funko Pops and keep track of their whole collection. In the future, it will implement a marketplace and a field where users can check the latest releases. Applied Technologies: JavaScript, MongoDB, React, Node.js, CSS, GraphQL, Apollo.js, and CSS.

Experience

Company: Custom Stone & Cabinet Fabricator; St. Petersburg, Florida; Nov 2020 - Jun 2021

Title: Project Manager

Role:

- Oversaw our team of fieldsmen at the worksites and collaborated with contractors on project start-ups such as blueprint analysis and field measurements.
- Organized the storage, management, and distribution of resources.
- Trained employees and subcontractors on how to utilize available tools and how to perform product installation.
- Provided periodic feedback to upper management on ways to optimize working processes and reduce operational costs, which my managers greatly appreciated.

Result:

- Three multi-family projects were completed from start to finish and another three were finished.
- The total cost of the projects including labor, materials, logistics were greatly reduced by my method of implementing a well-planned approach.
- The resources and workflow spreadsheets I designed for the business were so useful for the company that the owner and regional project manager decided to use them for all their projects. I essentially reinvented my role at the company and made it more vital to the company's success. The owners were sad to hear that I would be leaving to pursue software development, but they wish me well in this endeavor.

Company: GB Construction Services; Kissimmee, Florida, May 2018 - Nov 2020

Title: Project Manager

Role:

- Manager for a company that provides painting services for commercial construction jobs.
- Resources management, employee and subcontractor training, estimates for new projects, and daily reports for upper management.
- Ensure the quality of the finished products and manage our team to ensure all jobs were completed within the established time frame and budget.

Result:

• Our team successfully completed over 30 projects from start to finish to the great satisfaction of our contractors.

Company: RG Services LLC; Central Florida; Jun 2015 - May 2018

Title: General Manager/Owner

Role:

• Owner-Operator of residential properties restoration and remodeling. My team worked with restoration on properties damaged by wind, water or fire, and remodeling for residential properties. The working areas included framing, drywall, finish, carpentry, flooring, and painting.

Result:

• My team was able to finish several restoration projects in a timely manner thereby reducing any disruption to the customer's life and improving their satisfaction. Organization and planning played a key role in keeping the project costs low and profit margins higher.

Company: RS Farm Consulting Services; Goias, Brazil; June 2012 - Jan 2015

Title: Consultant Veterinarian

Role:

• Farm Specialized Veterinarian Consultant for 3 years with dairy and cattle farms all over the state of Goias.

• Provided a thorough analysis of the farm's current situation such as resources, production volume, livestock reproductive, productive system, and management. After data collection, a report would be created with a projection of expected productivity, cost, and net income. It would then be sent to the government credit lines to allow the farmers to obtain loans.

Result:

- Educated farmers on how to reduce their costs, increase the quality of the finished product, and ultimately increase net profits
- Provided a full perspective on the farm's situation and how it could be if some changes were rendered
- Some farmers were able to obtain government loans to help improve their business

Education

University of Central Florida - Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate 2021 Valencia College - BSCs Bachelor in Software Design and Development 2020 - 2022 Universidade Federal de Goiás - Bachelor in Veterinary Medicine 2006-2012